Ratnakar Sethi

Expert business strategist with extensive knowledge of organizational growth and sales. Over 6 years of experience offering companies with viable solutions to establishing organizational success as a skilled communicator. Innovative thinker who identifies more efficient ways of increasing company assets by recommending new items, revolutionizing existing product offers, and trying new market tactics.

#27, 4th cross, 7th main, Muniyappa Layout, G.B. Palya, Bangalore, Karnataka - 560068

> Mob: +91-8908587344 ratnakarsethi7344@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

IQnext Technologies. Pvt. Ltd.

Business Development Associate

Aug 2022 - Aug 2023

- Generate new leads through online or offline sources.
- Communicate and regular follow up to the leads to book an appointment for a meeting.
- Find out the exact requirements or pain points of the customer to present IQnext product in a useful way.
- Looking after end to end activities of sales from presentation to final payment.
- Selling SaaS based products for B2B sale, hence used to find out the correct turnkey to make the deal easier.
- Keeping a good relationship with the existing customer by providing them free updates on our software and seamless service on any fault detection.
- Take ownership of every deal such as software features, payment scheme, subscription type etc.
- Attend commercial & corporate events and exhibitions to present/showcase our software & its benefits as well as to attract /gather many leads to plan for business.

Flipkart Internet Pvt. Ltd.

Business Development Associate

July 2021 - July 2022

- Find new vendors in the market for some specific assigned categories and convert them to Flipkart Seller.
- Negotiating with sellers regarding discounts on some specific products which have less sales and also convince them to keep lesser delivery charges to make the deal more attractive.
- Help in business growth and brand improvement of the sellers. By encouraging them to register their brand in Flipkart by getting the Trademark certificate so that no other seller can latch on their product with the same brand name.
- Seller awareness on pricing and sales on Flipkart as per season and Sale events.
- Helping sellers in catalog creation, image selection and new product listing.
- Also convince existing sellers to add more different products at an attractive price to enlarge their business on Flipkart.

KEY SKILLS & HIGHLIGHTS

- Strong communication skills.
- Market analysis.
- Business skills.
- Organizational skills.
- Attention to details.
- Problem solving skills.
- Positive approach.

EDUCATIONAL SUMMARY

- B.A. from S.C.S. (A) college, Puri in 2014
- +2 Arts from S.C.S. Junior college, Puri in 2011
- 10th HSE board from Bholanath Vidyapith, Puri in 2009

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office proficient. (Excel, Word, Outlook, Power point)

Computer Hardware & Networking

- Hands on experience of about 5 years over SAP application in accounts payable process.
- MS SQL Server 2021, Microsoft SSMS

- Fulfilling business targets & Seller account management.
- Communicate with sellers and advise them on their business- related issues, market strategies and Flipkart policies.
- Competition market analysis e.g. to check for a product's market value & pricing range if it is a very commonly sold product, for example a jewelry item.

Siemens Technologies Services Pvt. Ltd.

Process Associate

Oct 2016 - July 2021

- Scrutinizing potential new leads and keeping on top of developments in the industry.
- Contacting prospective clients through a variety of mediums – this could include reaching out on social media, phoning or emailing.
- Verifying onboarding customer's documents such as registration certificate, product installation room specifications and other required documents for preboard verification.
- Holding presentations and demonstrations of products for potential clients.
- Communicating and informing updates to the existing clients in a way that supports an ongoing relationship by addressing their needs effectively.
- Managing customer retention in the ground of services such as extended warranty and AMC renewal etc.
- Working with cross functional stakeholders and colleagues to help align offerings as per the needs of clients.
- Assisting senior sales managers in finding leads and follow-ups, document collection, verifications etc.
- Keeping on top of administrative tasks such as updating CRM systems.
- Foster a collaborative environment within the organization. Research and identify new market opportunities.
- Communicating with internal stakeholders such as Procurement Team and Accounts Team and Engineers Team after onboarding for smoother delivery & installation of the product.

LANGUAGES KNOWN

- Odia (Mother Tongue)
- English (Proficient)
- Hindi (Proficient)